<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WeiSat – NFT</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NFT on WeiSat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>WEISAT</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 17:55:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NFT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/glossary/nft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 17:55:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/glossary/nft/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;An NFT, or Non-Fungible Token, is a special kind of digital item you can own, like a collectible card, a piece of art, or a song, stored on a blockchain (a secure digital record). The word “non-fungible” means it’s one-of-a-kind—there’s only one original version, and you can’t swap it for another NFT like you can with money or candy bars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of an NFT like a rare Pokémon card. Even if someone takes a picture of your card, only you own the real one, and the blockchain proves it’s yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;hx:overflow-x-auto hx:mt-6 hx:flex hx:rounded-lg hx:border hx:py-2 hx:ltr:pr-4 hx:rtl:pl-4 hx:contrast-more:border-current hx:contrast-more:dark:border-current hx:border-blue-200 hx:bg-blue-100 hx:text-blue-900 hx:dark:border-blue-200/30 hx:dark:bg-blue-900/30 hx:dark:text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;hx:ltr:pl-3 hx:ltr:pr-2 hx:rtl:pr-3 hx:rtl:pl-2&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hx:select-none hx:text-xl&#34; style=&#34;font-family: &#39;Apple Color Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Emoji&#39;, &#39;Segoe UI Symbol&#39;;&#34;&gt;ℹ️&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx:w-full hx:min-w-0 hx:leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx:mt-6 hx:leading-7 hx:first:mt-0&#34;&gt;Super Simple Analogy - Imagine buying a signed poster from your favorite singer. The signature makes it unique, and a digital “certificate” (the blockchain) proves it’s the real deal. That’s what an NFT is!&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have NFT for completely digital created product/content(Digital art) or Real world asset (RWD, Plot of land) created as token/NFT in blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As NFTs are unique digital assets on a blockchain, there are some standard defined in various blockchains like standar ERC-721 in Ethereum, to have a standardized approach of how to create (mint), transfer the NFT, or interact with it, so anyone in the world can interact with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NFT is usually a unique string (ID) whose information(metadata) are stored in the blockchain (most cases). If you are the owner of the asset-NFT, there is link to your &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/glossary/wallet&#34; &gt;wallet address&lt;/a&gt; and NFT(ID) is created and stored in the blockchain. When you transfer the ownership, the link with the new owner address and NFT ID is linked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until you make a transaction to transfer the ownership of the NFT to new owner, nobody can take or claim the ownership of the NFT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NFTs are often digital art, music, or virtual items, and you can buy or sell them on websites like NFT marketplace websites like &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensea.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OpenSea&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://rarible.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rarible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
